CONTACT

M: +355 69 99 32 340

W: lushka.al

E: anxhelo@lushka.al

U: Last updated on 2022-04-08

SUMMARY

Coming from a graphic design background, I transitioned into frontend development with a focus on performant, secure and accessible web experiences, as well as doing workshops and public speaking engagements on topics related to privacy-preserving technology.

I'm a heavy open source user and advocate. I contribute to various FOSS projects and am a member of the <u>Open Labs Hackerspace</u>, the first hackerspace in Albania. I also volunteer as a Fedora Linux Ambassador and The Document Foundation (LibreOffice) member.

I have organized tens of events and conferences, both locally and internationally, including OSCAL (<u>Open Source Conference Albania</u>), LibOCon (<u>LibreOffice Conference</u>), Linux Weekend and more.

Furthermore, I write <u>articles</u> on my website regarding events I participate in, security and privacy topics, tips and tricks regarding software and whatever I deem useful to write about.

I often <u>speak</u> about topics related to privacy and security on national TV shows and participate on active discussions.

EDUCATION

2015 - 2018, Polytechnic University of Tirana - Bachelor of Computer Engineering

Faculty of Information Technology, undergraduate and postgraduate education, as well as research and development in the fields of software engineering, object-oriented programming, computer architecture, design of digital systems, utilization systems, distributed and grid systems, network technologies and databases.

IELTS General Training Exam

Score: **8.5 out of 9**, CERF Level C2 Test Report Form Number **22AL000499LUSA001G**

ANXHELO LUSHKA

UX/UI Developer and DevOps Enginner

EXPERIENCE

FEBRUARY 2022 - PRESENT MAGOWARE - DEVOPS ENGINNER

<u>MAGOWARE</u> is a Software Company specialized in Video Content Management & Distribution Solutions through internet (IPTV/OTT) for different ecosystem actors & Paid TV operators.

My responsibilities and duties in this role are related to:

- Understanding customer requirements and project KPIs
- Implementing various development, testing, automation tools, and IT infrastructure
- Setting up tools and required infrastructure
- Defining and setting development, test, release, update, and support processes for DevOps operation
- Monitoring the processes during the entire lifecycle for its adherence and updating or creating new processes for improvement and minimizing the wastage
- Encouraging and building automated processes wherever possible
- Identifying and deploying cybersecurity measures by continuously performing vulnerability assessment and risk management
- Strive for continuous improvement and build continuous integration, continuous development, and constant deployment pipeline (CI/CD Pipeline)

MAY 2021 - APRIL 2022 TAHOE-LAFS - WEB DEVELOPER/DESIGNER (INTERNEWS CONTRACTOR)

<u>Tahoe-LAFS</u> is a Free and Open decentralized cloud storage system which distributes your data across multiple servers. Even if some of the servers fail or are taken over by an attacker, the entire file store continues to function correctly, preserving your privacy and security. In my role as a web developer, I was responsible for creating a new website and design system for the project, alongside creating all the necessary assets for social media and interweb.

- Creating a new asset management strategy and policy.
- Building and maintaining a new online presence and website for the project.
- Revising existing brand identity and creating a brand book.
- · Re-organization of current inventory.
- Updating and rebuilding an HTTP-based API.
- Keeping track of bugs, issues and progress using Trac tickets.
- Designing wireframes and mockups using Figma, to be implemented in code.
- · Creating new social media assets and guidelines.

JANUARY 2017 - PRESENT URA DESIGN - FRONTEND DEVELOPER/SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR

<u>Ura</u> is a digital studio which focuses on visual communication solutions tailored for Open Source and Internet Freedom projects. Ura was founded in 2016 in Albania to cater to the ever-rising demand for Usability and Design services in Open Source Software. We specialize in UX Design, Design Systems Research, Visual Identity and Web Development.

Our work can be seen across various Open Source projects such as <u>Mozilla</u>, <u>The Tor Project</u> and <u>The Linux Foundation</u>. In my role as frontend developer I am responsible for implementing pixel-perfect designs from provided mockups, creating live style guides and various custom-required systems. In my role as a system administrator, I ensure all our systems are up and running, updated and patched, including installing and maintaining new software related to our needs.

- Implementing web design and development principles to build stable software.
- Bringing mock-ups to life using HTML, CSS, JavaScript.
- Collaborating closely with the team to support projects during all phases of delivery.
- · Building websites and apps that are responsive and usable.
- Monitoring website performance and rectifying front-end-related issues.
- Providing guidance and troubleshooting support to clients.

SKILLS

- Web Development languages (HTML/ CSS/JavaScript)
- System Administration
- Networking (Servers, Switches etc.)
- Adobe Creative Suite
- Public speaking
- Analytical
- Creative
- Adaptable
- Independent
- Innovative
- Proactive
- Working in a team, under pressure and tight deadlines
- Fluid speaker in more than 3 languages (Albanian, English, Italian, Spanish etc.)
- Long time contributor and volunteer in open source projects

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

- Biking
- Travelling
- Photography
- · Listening to music
- Reading articles about astrophysics and the universe, scientific topics
- Spending time with friends and family
- Volunteering and organising events related to technology
- Sharing knowledge
- Participating in constructive debates

SOFTWARE

Technical

- Microsoft Windows
- Linux CLI and tools
- Microsoft Office/LibreOffice
- WordPress
- Wireshark/ZAP/Burp Suite
- Git/GitHub/GitLab
- Atlassian software
- VSCodium
- Mattermost/Slack

Design

- Figma
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe After Effects
- Inkscape
- GIMP
- Scribus
- Krita

ANXHELO LUSHKA

UX/UI Developer and DevOps Engineer

- Monitoring server event logs, performance logs, growth of data on the network, and checking the status of nightly/weekly/monthly server backups.
- Ensuring compliance with uptime and performance standards and develops system and product benchmarking and monitoring.
- Performing day-to-day maintenance and installation of server, network equipment, virtual machines, messaging, backups and storage.
- Working on moderately complex assignments, using judgment to resolve problems and make routine recommendations.
- Developing and maintaining detailed maintenance and contingency plans and documentation for server infrastructure.

SEPTEMBER 2016 - PRESENT FREELANCER

I have been offering freelancing services since 2016, in the field of graphic design, frontend development, system administration and deployment processes, from small to large clients.

- Analyzing marketing and user experience challenges and creating on-brand design solutions that meet measurable business goals and requirements.
- Collaborating with cross-functional design, development, and business teams to ensure all aspects of user experience have been thought through and optimized.
- Developing creative concepts and implementations that are consistently on target with brand objectives.
- Editing and formatting images for use on the web, in print, and in digital media
- · Using diverse inputs to identify and define exciting new concepts, opportunities, and
- · Implementing web design and development principles to build stable software.
- Bringing mock-ups to life using HTML, CSS, JavaScript.
- · Building websites and apps that are responsive and usable.
- Ensuring compliance with uptime and performance standards and develops system and product benchmarking and monitoring.
- Performing day-to-day maintenance and installation of server, network equipment, virtual machines, messaging, backups and storage.

JANUARY 2016 - PRESENT VOLUNTEER/EVENT ORGANIZER/MEMBER

Starting from 2016, I have organized and volunteered in more than 40 events, locally and internationally, related to technology and its impact on our daily lives. Some of them are:

- · Open Source Conference Albania (OSCAL) Volunteer and Organizer
- LibreOffice Conference Volunteer and Organizer
- Open Source Design Summit Organizer
- Underexposed Mentor
- FOSSCAMP Organizer
- · Linux Weekend Organizer
- · Wiki Weekend Organizer

I have given talks and held workshops on many events, the most interesting ones I would mention are:

- · Software Freedom Kosova 2016 and 2019
- · Prishtina Open Source Festival
- LibOCon (LibreOffice Conference) 2016, 2017, 2019
- ApacheCon Europe 2019
- Open Source Conference Albania 2017, 2018, 2019
- FOSSCAMP 2017
- · Linux Weekend 2016

Currently, I'm also a member of several open source projects and organizations, such as:

- Open Labs Hackerspace (Member) Collaborated with the local municipality to implement open source solutions in the administration
- Fedora Project (Ambassador)
- The Document Foundation (LibreOffice)
- Open Source Design (Core member)